Curriculum Vitae Ion Cojocaru

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Ion Cojocaru



bd. Mircea cel Batran 29, bl. 3, ap. 18, MD-2044, Chisinau, Republic of Moldova

+37379735153

https://cyber1609.herokuapp.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ion-cojocaru-7a2095b3/

Sex Male | Date of birth 16/09/1988 | Nationality Moldova

SUMMARY

New challenges make one's life more interesting - this is my main belief. I enjoy taking on new challenges, solving interesting problems and getting a perfect result. I am new to software development, but it is my favourite hobby so far. I've been learning algorithms and solving different problems for more than 15 years. Now I want to evolve my hobby into a career.

WORK EXPERIENCE

August 2011 – present

TSO Dispatcher

SE Moldelectrica

- Maintain power balance and inter-system energy exchange within operational hour.
- Read charts, meters, and gauges to monitor voltage and electricity flows.
- Check equipment and indicators to detect evidence of operating problems.
- Respond to emergencies, such as transformer or transmission line failures, and route current around affected areas.
- Direct personnel engaged in controlling or operating distribution equipment or machinery.
- Implement energy schedules, including real-time transmission reservations or schedules.
- Track conditions that could affect power needs, such as changes in the weather, and adjust equipment to meet any anticipated changes.
- Disturbance handling and remedial action.
- Enhance secure functioning of the power system.

Business or sector Energy

December 2019 – September 2020

Junior Web developer

Freelance

- Program, test and debug web applications.
- Design, develop, test and deploy web applications.
- Code pages, files, test, debug and deploy.
- Assist and support in the upkeep and maintenance of web sites.
- Fix bugs, troubleshoot and resolve problems.
- Work focused mainly on learning and on creating the site www.vam.md

Business or sector Computer Software

Curriculum Vitae Ion Cojocaru

September 2020 - present

Junior Web developer

BlueLine SRL

- Program, test and debug web applications, especially back-end.
- Design, develop, test and deploy web applications.
- Code pages, files, test, debug and deploy.
- Assist and support in the upkeep and maintenance of web sites.
- Fix bugs, troubleshoot and resolve problems.

Business or sector Computer Software

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2007 - 2013

Masters' degree

Technical University of Moldova

Engineering and engineering activities, Electrical Engineering

PERSONAL SKILLS

Technical skills

PHP, Laravel, Symfony, MySQL, Python, Django, Flask, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap 4, Git

Mother tongue(s)

Romanian

Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C1	C1	C2
C2	C2	C2	C2	C1

English Russian

Communication skills

- good communication skills gained through my experience as TSO dispatcher.
- continuous development of communication skills via web-based courses.

Organisational / managerial skills

- organizational skills
- teamwork
- leadership
- discipline
- multitasking